Guide to the Donald Gordon Papers, 1900-1988 UA.90.F46
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Expressionism: Art and Idea, III.
  - Images, 2.
    - Sotheby's Catalog, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Vytautas Kavolis, "The Social Structure of Artistic Expression", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - Sonderbund, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Piet Mondrian Catalog, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 68)
    - Varius Artists, Unlabeled (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - Salon Zolotoye Runo (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Yale University Press (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Catalogs (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Slides, Negatives, and Transparencies (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Expressionism Images, #1-10 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Expressionism Images, #11-20 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Expressionism Images, #21-30 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Expressionism Images, #31-40 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Expressionism Images, #41-50 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Expressionism Images, #51-60 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Expressionism Images, #61-70 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Expressionism Images, #71-80 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Expressionism Images, #81-90 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Expressionism Images, #91-100 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Expressionism Images, #101-110 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Expressionism Images, #111-120 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Expressionism Images, #121-130 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Expressionism Images, #131-140 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Expressionism Images, #141-150 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Expressionism Images, #151-160 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Expressionism Images, #161-170 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Expressionism Images, #171-180 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Expressionism Images, #181-190 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Expressionism Images, #191-201 (Box 19, Folder 25)
- Other Publications and Research, IV.
  This series includes articles and book manuscripts written by Donald Gordon. Also included are materials gathered by Dr. Gordon while researching his various projects. Some records, such as photographs and bibliographies, cannot be identified as pertaining to any one specific project.
  - Articles, 1.
    This subseries contains articles written by Donald Gordon. Of note are files on "Kirchner in Dresden," Dr. Gordon's award winning article from the Art Bulletin. These articles reflect Dr. Gordon's interest in Modern Art, particularly Expressionism.
    - "Alechinsky: An Appeal to the Spirit", 1977 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Article Regarding Kirchner (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - "Counter-Clockwise Time: Studies in Self-Expression 1900-1920", Article Proposal (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - "Expressionism & It's Publics", 1975 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - "Expressionism: An Introductory Study; E.L. Kirchner in Dresden: 1901-1911", 1952 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - "Expressionism: Content by Contradiction" (1982), Art in America, Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 31-32)
    - "Expressionism: Expressionists and Modern Art Criticism", 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - "Gauguin Book Review" (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Gordon Thesis Drafts (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - "Kandinsky in New York" (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - "Kirchner in Berlin" (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "Kirncher in Dresden," Correspondence and Awards (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Kirchner in Dresden," Correspondence after Publication (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Kirchner in Dresden," part 1 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Kirchner in Dresden," part 2, draft manuscript (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Kirchner in Dresden," Pictoral Supplement, Art Bulletin, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Kunst und Wirklichkeit: die amerikanische Malerei in drei Jahrhunderten" (Art and Reality: the American Painters in three Centuries) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Marc & Friedrich: Expressionism as Departure from Romanticism", 1981 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Marc & Friedrich: Expressionism as Departure from Romanticism", Manuscript, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "On the Origin of the Word Expressionism", 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "On the Origin of the Word 'Expressionism," London Proof (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Pollock's 'Bird'—Or How Jung Did Not Offer Much Help In Myth-Making" (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Polykleitos' Diadoumenos: Animation and Measurement" (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "Rolf Nesch and German Expressionism" (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - "The Several Expressionisms: The Gloom-And-Doom Factor" (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "Style and Society: The Early Pollock 1933-1945" (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Book Manuscripts, 2.
    This subseries contains unpublished monographs in various stages of completion. Elements of some of these projects appear in Dr. Gordon's book Expressionism: Art and Idea.
    - Expressionism: the Other Face of the Avant Garde, Draft (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Expressionism: the Other Face of the Avant Garde (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Expressionism: the Other Face of the Avant Garde, Notes (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Monsters of the Mind: the Psychology of Self-Expression, Draft, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 18-19)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, part 1 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, with bibliography, part 1 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Chapter 1-6 Bibligoraphy and Layout (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Chapter 7 Bibligoraphy and Layout (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Chapter 8 Bibligoraphy and Layout (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Draft (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Research (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Expressionism in Modern Art and Society, Notes (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - German Expressionism: New Perspectives, Research and Notes (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified Bibliography, 3.
    This bibliography was created by Dr. Gordon as a general resource or for a specific unidentified project.
    - Surveys - General
      - General (surveys) (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Theory and Criticism (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Painting (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Art and Self (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Art and Society (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Movements
      - Abstract Art (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Cubism (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - Contemporary Writings (Literature, Eyewitnesses) (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - Futurism (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Countries
      - Russia (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Artists - non-German
      - Artists non-German (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Sculpture
      - Sculpture (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Boccioni (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Georges Braque (Box 18, Folder 33)
      - Burliuk, D. (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - Robert and Sonia Delauney (Box 18, Folder 35)
      - Andre Derain (Box 18, Folder 36)
      - Marcel Duchamp (Box 18, Folder 37)
      - Michel Larionov (Box 18, Folder 38)
      - Wyndham Lewis (Box 18, Folder 39)
      - Kazemir Malevich (Box 18, Folder 40)
      - John Marin (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - Piet Mondrian (Box 18, Folder 42)
      - Pablo Picasso (Box 18, Folder 43)
      - Weber (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - International Expressionism
      - International Expressionism (Box 18, Folder 45)
      - Belgium (Box 18, Folder 46)
      - Czechoslovakia (Box 18, Folder 47)
      - France (Box 18, Folder 48)
      - Great Britain (Box 18, Folder 49)
      - Hungary (Box 18, Folder 50)
      - Netherlands (Box 18, Folder 51)
      - Poland (Box 18, Folder 52)
      - Russia (Box 18, Folder 53)
      - South Africa (Box 18, Folder 54)
      - Sweden (Box 18, Folder 55)
      - United States (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Art and Myth, Symbol, Transformation
      - Art and Myth, Symbol, Transformation (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Science and Art
      - Science and Art (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - Literature and Art
      - Literature and Art (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - Politics and Art
      - Politics and Art (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - Theory and Content (general)
      - Theory and Content (general) (Box 18, Folder 61)
      - Regress: Longing, Primitivism, Union (Box 18, Folder 62)
    - Movements - Groups
      - Blaue Reiter (Box 18, Folder 63)
      - Brücke (Box 18, Folder 64)
      - Entartete Kunst (Box 18, Folder 65)
      - German and Austrian Expressionism (Box 18, Folder 66)
      - New Objectivity (Box 18, Folder 67)
      - Novembergruppe (Box 18, Folder 68)
      - Sturm (Box 18, Folder 69)
    - Artists - German, Swiss, Austrian
      - Ernst Barlach (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Max Beckmann (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Otto Dix (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Lyonel Feininger (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - George Grosz (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Erich Heckel (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Alexej Jawlensky (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Wassily Kandinsky (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Ernst Kirchner (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Paul Klee (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Oskar Kokoschka (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Käthe Kollwitz (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Wilhelm Lehmbruck (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Franz Marc (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Ludwig Meidner (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Heinrich Nauen (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Emil Nolde (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - Max Pechstein (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - Egon Schiele (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - Karl Schmidt-Rottluff (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Other Artists (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Architecture - German Expressionism
      - General (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Taut Circle (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - Bauhaus (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Film - German Expressionism
      - German Film (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Literature - German Expressionism (General Movement Docs First)
      - Expressionist Movement Arts in Germany (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - Literature and Drama (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Music - German Expressionism
      - German Music (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Regress: Longing, Primitivism, Union
      - Regress: Longing, Primitivism, Union (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Apocolyptic Destruction
      - Apocolyptic Destruction (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - General Bibliography
      - General Bibliography (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - July-September 1967 (Box 22, Folder 32)
      - Munich, Paris, October-December 1967 (Box 22, Folder 33)
      - October and November 1967 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Sturm, Berlin
      - Sturm, Berlin (Box 22, Folder 35)
      - Sturm 1, 1910-1911 (Box 22, Folder 36)
      - Sturm 2, 1911-1912 (Box 22, Folder 37)
      - Sturm 3, 1912-1913 (Box 22, Folder 38)
      - Sturm 4, 1913-1914 (Box 22, Folder 39)
      - Sturm 5 and Sturm 6, 1914-1916 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Paris Trips
      - Paris Trips (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Photographs, 4.
    This subseries includes photographs of different works of art, primarily examples of Expressionism. The collection includes artwork done by notable artists such as Robert Delauney, as well as unattributed or unidentifiable works.
    - Chronik KG Brücke (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Important Documents (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Photo Paper Images (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Brücke Group misc. prints and documents (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Burnt Paper (large size), sketches (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Images on card-like paper (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Transparent paper sketches (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Collector Dr. Fischer (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - California Museums (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Unattributed collection (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Museums - Scotland (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Swiss Collectors (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Collector - W.G.R. Allen (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - MOMA (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - New York Museums (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Various Art Museums (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Van der Goltz - Collector (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Collector - E. Gottlieb (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Collector Dr. Getker (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Mexico City Collector (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - German Collectors (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - German Museums (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Unnatributed Collector and Museums (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Unattributed Sketches (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Sketches - geschnitten (cut) (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Sketches - flecken (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Kirchner - drawings (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Budezier (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - M. Gersprach (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Kirchner diary and Girsebrach diaries (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Massechusetts Museums (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Marion Koogler McIvy Art Institute (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - American Collector (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Unattributed Delauney (name and dates) (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1904-1905 (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1905-1907 (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1907-1908 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Robert Delauney works July XXIII series, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1908-1909 (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1910-1911 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1912-1913 (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Robert Delauney works, 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Sonia Delauney works, 1904-1909 (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - Sonia Delauney works, 1913-1914 (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - Frits van den Berghe (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - Ingman Bergman's production of Strindberg's A Dream Play (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - Jean Brouselmans (Box 21, Folder 60)
    - Hippolyte Daeye (Box 21, Folder 61)
    - Jean Deleille (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - James Ensor (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - Laemans Eugin (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Henri Euenpoel (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - De la Faille (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - A. D. Goncharov (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - Auguste Herbin (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Gustave de Longhe (Box 21, Folder 69)
    - Fernand Khnopff (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - Eugine Laermans (Box 21, Folder 71)
    - I. F. Larionov (Box 21, Folder 72)
    - Lemmen Georges (Box 21, Folder 73)
    - Paul Maas (Box 21, Folder 74)
    - V. N. Masyutin (Box 21, Folder 75)
    - Constantin Heunier (Box 21, Folder 76)
    - Edvard Munch (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - Constant Permeke (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - Theo van Ryusselberghe (Box 21, Folder 79)
    - Valerius de Saedeleer (Box 21, Folder 80)
    - Albert Servaes (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - Gustave de Smet (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - Edgard Tytgar (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - Gustave van de Woestyne (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - Henry Van De Velde (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - Rick Wauters (Box 21, Folder 86)
    - Rudolf Wilke (Box 21, Folder 87)
    - V. D. Zamirailo (Box 21, Folder 88)
  - Research, 5.
    These research files were maintained by Dr. Gordon as either a general resource or for a specific unidentified project. Included are auction catalogs, articles, and photographs of artwork.
    - Auction Catalogs, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 89)
    - Ebbi Komodie Max Beckmann Photos (Box 21, Folder 90)
    - Exhibition and Symposium Announcements, 1964-1984 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Nieuwe Beweging Photos (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Papers, Articles, and Abstracts (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
    - Photographs of Catalog (Box 22, Folder 5-6)
    - Psychology - Meaning Expressive and Symbolic (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
    - Research Notes and Articles on Expressionism (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
    - Russian Research on Expressionism (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified Expressionist Art (Box 22, Folder 13-19)
- Professional Papers, V.
  This series contains Dr. Gordon's correspondence with colleagues and contacts throughout the art community. Also included are files pertaining to his work as a professor of fine arts, which contain lectures and other course materials. Records pertaining to Dr. Gordon's grants and fellowship work are also present.
  - Correspondence, 1.
    The subseries contains letters and notes to and from Dr. Gordon dating from 1958 to 1984. The correspondents include professional collogues and friends.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 4-6)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 7-10)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 16-17)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
    - Correspondence and Notes, September-December 1980 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Grants and Fellowships, 2.
    The subseries pertains to the grants and fellowships that Donald Gordon received throughout his career. These accolades include the American Council for Learned Societies, the American Philosophical Society, and the Fulbright-Hays Act Scholarship. Also included is Dr. Gordon's curriculum vitae.
    - American Council for Learned Societies, 1963-1969 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - American Council for Learned Societies, 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - American Council for Learned Societies, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - American Council for Learned Societies, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - American Council for Learned Societies, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - PSC-CUNY Research Award Program, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Commitee on International Exchange of Persons, 1963-1969 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Dickinson College Faculty Research Grant, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Fulbright-Hays Act Scholarship, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Various Correspondence Letters and Notes, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Research Trip to Germany, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
  - Instruction, 3.
    The subseries contains information about courses taught by Donald Gordon at the University of Pittsburgh, as well as lectures he gave at various locations and events. These records span from 1972 to 1983.
    - Lectures, 1.
      The collection houses the lectures given by Gordon from 1972 to 1983. Many of these lectures were presented outside of the University of Pittsburgh in places such as the Museum of Modern Art, National Gallery, and the Westmoreland County Museum of Art. Other lectures were given at universities such as Carnegie Mellon, Yale, and Columbia.
      - "'Ye Must be Born Again": Kirchner's Poster for the Neue Secession and Expressionist Beginnings in Berlin, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
      - A Painter's Nekyia: The Uses of Myth in Kokoschk's Art, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - "Art and Reality," Carnegie Mellon University, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - "Art Development in Child and Culture" (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - "Bruecke Art and the Hunger for Wholeness" (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - "Egon Schiele and Expressionist Art", 1981 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - "Egon Schiele, George Grosz and the German Identity Problem" (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - "Expressionism as Modernism," Yale (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Expressionism, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Jung Lecture (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Lecture on Audience (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - "Ludwig Meider and the End of the World", 1978 (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - "Metaphor, Metamorphosis and Meaning in Early Modern Art," Columbia University, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 22-23)
      - German Expressionism and Modernism, National Gallery, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - "Oskar Kokoschka and the Visionary Tradition" - CAA, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - "Picasso," Westmoreland County Museum of Art, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - Primitivism and Expressionism Lecture, Los Angeles, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - "Primitivism and German Expressionist Sculpture" (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - "Self-Expression and Self-Criticism" Parts 1 and 2 (Box 24, Folder 29)
      - "6 Women Modernists," Westmoreland County Museum of Art, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 30)
      - "The Expressionist Moment in Fauvism," Museum of Modern Art (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - "The German Youth Revolution Against the Evil Father (Concerning the Origins of the Holocaust)", 1978 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Course Material, 2.
      This section contains information on a variety of courses taught by Dr. Gordon during his professorship at the University of Pittsburgh. Many of the classes pertain to various aspects of Modern Art and the files include bibliographies, teaching assistant and lecture notes, course proposals, syllabi, exams, and reading assignments.
      - Bibliographies (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - Bibliography: Constructivism (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - Book inventory: personal collection (Box 24, Folder 35)
      - Art History Methods: Class and Seminar (Box 24, Folder 36)
      - Class: Cezanne, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 37)
      - Class: Contemporary Art, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 38)
      - Class: Cubism, 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 39)
      - Class: Expressionism, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 40)
      - Class: Identity Crisis and Modern Art, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Class: New York School, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Class: Picasso, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Class: Surrealism, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - CAS Committee on General Education in the Humanities (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Art History Methods (Henderson) (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Humanities Class: Adolescence (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Interdisciplenary Seminar (Eng/FA/Music): Modernism, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Art and Politics in Modern Germany - Seminar, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Seminar: Beckmann, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Seminar: Expressionism, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 11-12)
      - Seminar: Expressionism and Primitivism, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Seminar: New York School, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Seminar: New York School, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Seminar: Symbolism and Modern Art, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 16-17)
      - Seminar: Topics in Modern Art: "Times", 1974 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Protocol for Advanced Methodology Seminar, Spring 1988 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - TA notes: Art of the Orient, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - TA notes: Northern Renaissance Art, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - TA notes: Early Chinese Painting, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - TA notes: Topics in Modern Art, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 23)